GLORY
DAYS!
The great invasion of the State of Wei plan.
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）魏(ぎ)の国への大攻略戦
Having been victorious in the first battle, the State of Qin Army was off to a great start.
その初戦に勝利した秦国(しんこく)軍は
順調な滑り出しとなった
But at this point, no one in the State of Qin had yet realized
しかし このとき まだ
秦国軍は 誰も気づいていなかった
この遠征の先で 思いも寄らぬ
大人物と対決することを
that later on in this campaign they would confront an unimaginably grand figure.
The people of Qin have invaded my kingdom
（景湣王(けいびんおう)）
秦の者どもが 我が国に侵攻し
虚中(きょちゅう) 虚西(きょさい)まで あっさりと陥落した
and easily captured everything from central to West Xu.
But the reason I am not shaken whatsoever is because you are here.
だが―
我が心胆が
一切 震えることがないのは―
そなたがいるからだ
Former member of the State of Zhao Three Great Devas,
元趙国三大天(ちょうこく さんだいてん)
Great General Lian Po!
廉頗(れんぱ)大将軍
そなたが我が国に亡命してより３年
It has been three years since you defected to my kingdom.
There is nothing I have ever been more thankful for.
今ほど
ありがたく思ったことはないぞ
The Man Lian Po
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）
信(しん)の初陣となった蛇甘(だかん)平原の戦い
Several months before Xin's first campaign, the battle at Shegan Plain,
秦国軍 麃公(ひょうこう)と 魏国軍 呉慶(ごけい)が
対決した あの戦いがあった年
where the State of Qin Army led by Biao Gong fought the State of Wei Army led by Wu Qing,
その数か月前にも 実は別の所で
大きな戦が起こっていた
there was actually another great battle happening elsewhere.
( Flags - Zhao )
This battle went down in history
「史記」にも
記されている この戦いは―
春秋時代においても
極めて異質なものであった
as a particularly odd battle, even for the Spring and Fall Period.
That is because it was a clash between the State of Zhao Army and the State of Zhao Army.
それは 趙国軍 対 趙国軍の
激突だったのである
（斬る音）
（趙兵たち）ウワーッ！
（廉頗）ンンッ！
（趙兵）ウワッ！
Lian Po
State of Zhao Three Great Devas
The Three Great Devas were the people celebrated as the three greatest generals of the State of Zhao.
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）三大天とは
趙国が誇る３人の大将軍である
They were heroes purported to be at the same level as the Six Great Generals of the State of Qin.
王騎(おうき)将軍ら秦国六大将軍と
並び称される英雄で―
Their terrific fighting capability and military records roared throughout all of China.
そのすさまじい武力と戦績により
中国全土に名をとどろかせていた
And one of those Three Great Devas was Lian Po.
その三大天の１人こそが廉頗である
Lian Po is coming! Stop him!
（騎兵）廉頗が来るぞ！ 止めろ！
Wh-What's going on?! Our opponent is a general of our own state!
（歩兵Ａ）ど… どうなってんだ！
相手は 同じ趙国軍なのに！
And isn't Lian Po a hero of our state, Great General Lian Po?!
（歩兵Ｂ）し… しかも 廉頗とは
我が国の英雄
廉頗大将軍ではないのか！
一体 どうして こんな…
Why the hell is this happening?!
General Lian Po isn't stopping!
（部下Ａ）
廉頗将軍 止まりません！
（部下Ｂ）
くそ！ 楽乗(がくじょう)さま このままでは…
Dammit!
Lord Yue Chang, if this keeps up...
（楽乗）うろたえるな
第４陣 左翼に差し込み 分断せよ
Do not panic.
Yue Chang
State of Zhao General
Fourth Formation, enter the left flank and split it apart.
Yes, sir!
We have fought together for 20 years.
（楽乗）20年 共に戦ってきた
I have full knowledge of General Lian Po's fighting style.
廉頗将軍の戦い方は
全て 頭に入っている
（部下Ｃ）
おお！ さすがは楽乗大将軍
I knew we could count on you, Great General Yue Chang!
（部下Ｂ）この戦 もらったぞ！
This war is ours!
General Lian Po, just what in the world are you thinking?
廉頗将軍
一体 何を考えておるのだ？
The origin of this strange battle between comrades
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）同士討ちという
この異色の戦いの発端は―
この年
趙国王に即位した悼襄王(とうじょうおう)にある
is the man who was enthroned as King of Zhao this year, King Daoxiang.
From when he was only the crowned prince, the ill-mannered King Daoxiang was frequently remonstrated by Lian Po.
太子(たいし)のころより素行の悪い悼襄王は
しばしば 廉頗に いさめられていた
This twisted king hated this from the bottom of his heart.
ゆがんだ性格の王は
これを心底 恨みに思っており―
国王に即位するや 遠征中の廉頗に
大将軍剥奪を言い渡したのである
As soon as he took the throne,
he announced the revocation of Lian Po's title of general while Lian Po was out on campaign.
Lian Po of course rejected this senseless dismissal.
理不尽な この更迭を
廉頗は当然 拒否した
Enraged by this, King Daoxiang raised an army of a remarkable 50,000 men,
これに激高した悼襄王は
なんと ５万の軍を起こし
and ordered Yue Chang to "defeat the traitor Lian Po".
“逆賊 廉頗を討て”と
楽乗に命じたのである
Yue Chang was a member of the family called geniuses by the famed Zhuge Kongming,
楽乗とは あの諸葛孔明(しょかつこうめい)をして
天才と言わしめた楽毅(がくき)の一族である
the Yueyi clan.
Yue Chang was Zhao's best general after Lian Po.
楽乗は
廉頗に次ぐ趙国第２の将軍であり
その実力は ひそかに“廉頗を
しのぐのでは”とウワサされていた
It was rumored that his ability secretly surpassed Lian Po's.
General Lian Po, I know how irrational it is, but this is the king's decree.
（楽乗）廉頗将軍 理不尽は
承知ですが これは王の命です
Please General, allow me to take control of your soldiers and return to Handan for now.
どうか 将軍の兵を私に預け
一度 邯鄲(かんたん)に お戻りください
（廉頗）フン…
General...
将軍…
If you do not comply, then I, Yue Chang,
さもなくば この楽乗
力ずくで 将軍を
邯鄲まで お連れせねばなりません
must bring you to Handan by force.
Do you think you can do that?
うぬに できるのか？ そんなことが
I would not like to do it, but if I must...
やりたくはありませんが
必要とあらば
We have a force of 50,000. General, you have 8,000.
（楽乗）こちらは５万に対し
将軍の兵は８千
そちらに
あらがうすべは ありません
There is no way for you to oppose us.
Interesting.
面白い
I will begin. Prepare yourself.
わしから仕掛けてやる　準備せよ
Wha?! General, wait!
あっ… 将軍 お待ちを！
Do you know what will happen to you if you do that?!
そんなことをしては
ご自身が どうなるか…
I cannot understand... Why he would do such a thing...
（楽乗）理解に苦しむ
なぜ こんなバカなことを…
Does he have some sort of plan...?
何か思うところでもあったのか
But it's too late now.
だが もはや手遅れだ
Now that we've crossed swords, I, Yue Chang, shall not hold back.
一度 斬り結べば
この楽乗 手加減は 一切せぬぞ
ウワッ！
The central unit led by General Lian Po has been destroyed! Destroyed!
（部下Ａ）廉頗将軍率いる
中央部隊が崩壊！ 崩壊です！
（歓声）
（部下Ｃ）か… 壊滅？
Th-The Lian Po unit was wiped out?!
廉頗隊が！
（部下Ｂ）よし！
Yes!
（部下Ｄ）
おお！ 廉頗将軍を討ち取ったぞ！
We've defeated General Lian Po!
The Yue Chang Army is the strongest in all of Zhao...!
（部下Ｂ）
この楽乗軍こそ 趙国最強…
（部下たち）ウワーッ！
So, how 'bout it, Yue Chang. Do ya give up?
どうじゃ？ 楽乗　まいったか？
I-I give up.
ま… まいりました
ハハハハッ！
そうじゃろう そうじゃろう
Oh, ya do?!
（輪虎(りんこ)）はい 没収
（楽乗軍将Ａ）クッ…
Okay, confiscated.
（楽乗軍将Ｂ）れ… 廉頗将軍！
General Lian Po!
こんなことをして
正気の沙汰ではない！
You must be out of your mind!
You already cannot go back to the State of Zhao!
（楽乗軍将Ｃ）
もはや 趙国には帰れませぬぞ！
Oh, I don't plan on going back!
（廉頗）おう 帰るつもりはない！
（楽乗たち）ハッ…
（廉頗）悼襄王… ありゃダメじゃ
King Daoxiang, that's really not gonna work out.
前の王も相当じゃったが
今度は たまらぬ
The last king wasn't great, but this one I really can't stand.
There's nothing stupider than working under an idiot!
バカの下で働くことほど
バカなことはないぞ
ハハハハッ！
（楽乗軍将Ｃ）廉頗将軍！
General Lian Po!
Is he intending to abandon his country?
（楽乗）まさか 国を捨てる気で？
I am disappointed!
（楽乗）失望しましたぞ
（廉頗）うん？
Did it mean that little to you?
そんなに軽いのですか？ これまで
将軍の築き上げてきたものは
All you've built up thus far as a general?
Did you care that little of the State of Zhao?!
そんなに軽かったのですか！
趙国への思いは！
My feelings towards war are much grander!
（廉頗）戦への思いのほうが
はるかに重い！
戦で育まれ
戦で全土に名をとどろかせ
I was raised on war, and made my name echo across the lands with war.
強敵たちと出会い それらと
全身全霊をささげて戦った
I met with great enemies and gave up all of my body and soul to fight with them.
戦が 廉頗の全てだ
War is what Lian Po is!
それを…
So...
So why the hell was I stripped of my title of general?!
それを なにが大将剥奪か！
（輪虎）うわぁ…
神聖な戦場に 泥を
投げ込むようなことを言いおって！
How dare that idiot king sling mud onto the sacred battlefield!
And how dare those idiot retainers allow it!
バカ王が！
それを許す家臣もバカぞろいじゃ！
That royal palace is nothing but an assembly hall of pigs!
王宮は ブタの集会場か！
（楽乗）ンンッ…
楽乗
（楽乗）うん？
Yue Chang.
Your wars were pretty good.
うぬの戦 なかなか良かったぞ
このわしが
ヒヤリとする場面が 何度かあった
There were plenty of scenes that gave me chills.
まあ それでも しかし―
Well, even so...
compared to those State of Qin guys,
秦国のあやつらに比べれば―
腹八分目… いや
腹六分目といったところだがのぅ
You're just short of a full meal. A bit a ways.
These battlefields really are lonely without them...
やはり ヤツらの消えた戦場は
寂しいということか
It seems... that these men had different roles from the start.
（楽乗）どうやら この方たちとは
初めから 役者が違ったようだ
And so, Lian Po took with him
his long-time subordinate officers
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）こうして 廉頗は―
生え抜きの将校たちを引き連れて
魏の国に亡命した
and defected to the State of Wei.
Three years have passed since then.
それから３年 廉頗は 一度も
魏国軍を率いようとはしなかった
And Lian Po has never once tried to lead a State of Wei army.
( Flag - Wei )
But...!
だが―
The Great General has shown the intent to stand on the battlefield once again, hoisting the Wei flag.
魏の旗を掲げて 再び
大将軍は 戦場に立つ意思を示した
As a former member of the State of Zhao Three Great Devas,
かつて 趙国三大天として―
王騎ら秦国六大将軍たちと
互角に渡り合ってきた―
he fought on par with Wang Qi and the other Six Great Generals.
But now, what the monstrous general Lian Po has his eyes on is...
猛将 廉頗の目が
今 捉えているのは…
of course, the ones currently invading the State of Wei, the State of Qin Meng Ao Army.
無論 魏の国に侵攻中の
秦国 蒙驁(もうごう)軍である
We've been waiting for you, my lord.
（介子坊(かいしぼう)）
お待ちしておりました 殿
You guys, eh?
うぬらか
さすがじゃ　もう嗅ぎつけたか
I should've known you'd catch wind of this.
It was so mean of you not to tell us, the Four Heavenly Kings a thing about this.
（輪虎）ひどいな　四天王の僕らに
相談ひとつないなんて
ヌハハハッ！
そのわりには 随分 うれしそうだな
You seem quite happy nonetheless, eh?!
Indeed, we are.
それは そうですよ
When we thought of seeing your gallant figure in battle once again,
殿の雄姿が 再び見られるとなると
胸躍って 体が宙に浮きそうですよ
our hearts pounded and we felt like we'd fly right off the ground.
Heavenly King Lun Hu,
“廉頗四天王”
その響きも懐かしいわい
that voice of yours really takes me back.
It has been three years,
３年ぶりじゃが…
Xuan Feng
Lian Po Four Heavenly Kings
Xuan Feng!
玄峰(げんぽう)
（玄峰）はっ！
Sir.
Jiang Yan
Lian Po Four Heavenly Kings
Jiang Yan!
姜燕(きょうえん)
（姜燕）はっ…
Sir.
Jie Zifang
Lian Po Four Heavenly Kings
Jie Zifang!
介子坊
（介子坊）はっ…
Sir.
Lun Hu
Lian Po Four Heavenly Kings
Lun Hu.
輪虎
（輪虎）は～い
Yes, sir!
Your skills haven't rusted, have they?
うぬら 腕はサビておるまいな？
（４人）はっ！
No, sir!
フッ… 輪虎
（輪虎）はいは～い
Lun Hu.
Yes, sir?!
The usual fare.
いつもどおりだ　先に出て 敵の
めぼしい将校の首を狩ってまいれ
You go on ahead and hunt the heads of any outstanding enemy officers.
部下は 3,000ほどいればいいか？
（輪虎）あ～ 大丈夫です
Would 3,000 subordinates be enough?
Ah, it's okay.
For such a mission, my 300-Man Unit would be plenty.
その任なら
僕の三百人隊くらいで十分です
Lian Po
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）開戦より ひと月
秦国軍の蒙驁本陣は―
One month since the start of the war.
The State of Qin Army's Meng Ao headquarters is approaching their third castle, the Jinli Barrier.
３つ目の城 近利関(きんりかん)に
さしかかっていた
H-Hey, you bastards!
（番陽(ばんよう)）こ… こら 貴様ら！
Don't just climb our siege tower without permission!
勝手に 井蘭車(せいらんしゃ)に上るな！
これは わしらの物だろうが！
This is ours!
（信）うるせえ！
この井蘭者は みんなの物(もん)だ！
Shaddup! This siege tower belongs to all of us!
Like hell it—
（番陽）ふざけ… アアッ！
All right! We made it up the castle walls!
（尾平(びへい)）しゃ！ 城壁に上ったぞ！
（兵士たち）オーッ！
（斬る音）
（魏兵）ウワッ！
Go, Feixin Unit!
行け 飛信(ひしん)隊！
Don't let those Yufeng Unit idiots get all the credit!
玉鳳(ぎょくほう)隊にばっか
手柄を上げさせんな！
（斬る音）
（魏兵たち）ウワッ！
Don't let them win again! Go!
（壁長）
そう何度もやらせるか　行け！
（斬る音）
（魏兵たち）ウワッ！
Lord Xin, the enemy's numbers are far higher than we anticipated!
（渕(えん)）信どの！
敵の数が予想より はるかに多い！
Makes sense, this is the third time!
（信）さすがに３度目だ
ヤツらも準備してやがったんだ
They're getting better prepared!
（渕）
我らと玉鳳隊でも これは厳しい
Even for both us and the Yufeng Unit, this is a hard fight!
Hey, you bastards down there!
こら！ 下にいる てめえら！
Quit spacing out! Climb the siege tower on the double!
ボ～ッとしてねえで
井蘭車で さっさと上ってこい！
There's a mountain of achievements up for grabs on these walls!
城壁の上は 手柄の山だぞ！
（どよめき）
S-Stop! Don't climb that!
や… やめろ！ 上るな！
この井蘭車は
人数制限があるんだぞ！
There's a limit to how many people can be on this siege tower!
Th-That many people is too much!
そ… そんな大勢ではムリだ！
や… やめろ！
S-Stop!
It'll collapse!
壊れる！
Ah, this is pleasant.
（蒙恬(もうてん)）へ～え… これは楽ちん
（番陽）うん？
あっ！ 蒙恬 貴様まで！
Even you, you bastard, Meng Tian?!
（信）気をつけろ！ 来るぞ！
Be careful! They're coming!
A heavy infantry unit.
（王賁(おうほん)）重装歩兵隊…
Yufeng Unit! Get in rank!
（王賁）玉鳳隊 隊列を組め
All right!
しゃ！ 出番だぞ てめえら！
（王賁）ハッ…
It's our turn, you bastards!
（中鉄(ちゅうてつ)･田有(でんゆう)･竜川(りゅうせん)）ウオーッ！
いけ！
Go!
The super-strong-three of the Feixin Unit!
飛信隊 怪力三人衆！
Okay, head in there!
よし 中に入り込め！
（崇原(すうげん)･去亥(きょがい)）よっしゃ！
Okay!
（刺す音）
（魏兵）ウワッ！
（魏兵たち）ウワッ！
（蒙恬）へ～え…
Just as you'd expect, because of all the experience they've gained
さすがに場数を踏んでるだけあって
そこらの歩兵隊より 格段に強い
they're much stronger than those foot soldiers.
And additionally...
加えて そこに…
（斬る音）
（魏兵たち）ウワッ！
ヤッ！
the captain and vice captain's extraordinary swordsmanship over there.
隊長と副隊長のケタ外れの剣術
飛信隊…
The Feixin Unit...
They're a bit rough around the edges, but their destructive power is something to be reckoned with.
アラはあるが破壊力は相当なものだ
It looks like General Wang Qi appointing them as a special unit wasn't just for show.
あの王騎将軍から
特殊部隊を任命されたのは―
伊達(だて)ではないってことか
But even so...
にしても…
（斬る音）
（魏兵たち）ウワッ！
（蒙恬）あの副長 ヤバすぎ
That vice captain is seriously dangerous.
（王賁）フン…
All right, go, go!
（信）おら 行け行け！
うん？ 何だ？ あやつら
What are those guys doing?
They're moving in the direction opposite the stairway.
階段と逆のほうへ進んでいくぞ
なっ…
Ah! Those guys, they have rope!
あやつら 縄を！
C-Could it be they're intending to imitate our strategy?!
ま… まさか
わしらの作戦をマネする気か！
Hey, you bastards! Do you have no pride?!
こら！ 貴様ら そんなことまでして
誇りはないのか！
Shut up!
うるせえ！
Our pride is in not carrying any sorta cheap pride!
チンケな誇りなんざ
持ち合わせてねえのが俺らの誇りだ
You must be kidding!
ふざけるな！ そんな誇りがあるか
（蒙恬）ハハハハッ！
What the hell sort of pride is that?!
Okay, let's go, Long Chuan!
いくぞ 竜川！ しっかり持ってろ
Hold on tight!
Hold on a second, Xin!
（蒙恬）あっ… ちょっと待て 信！
They're already onto your plan!
その作戦は もうバレてる！
They've got tons of enemy soldiers ready and waiting in front of the castle gate!
城門前は
ぎっしり 敵兵が待ち構えてるぞ！
いや その前に そもそも…
No, even before that...
Lord Xin! You're in the wrong place!
信どの！ 場所がズレてる！
（尾平）そこは城門の上じゃねえ！
That's not above the gate!
Hot!
あちっ！
（田有･中鉄）あっ！
えっ？ ウッ… ウワーッ！
Lord Xin!
信どのーっ！
Idiot.
（羌瘣(きょうかい)）バカ
（尾平）あっ！ 動いた！
He moved!
（渕）
生きてる！ 信どのは生きてるぞ！
He's alive!
Lord Xin is alive!
フフッ… まったく
Geez.
If he weren't such an idiot, he really could be a formidable rival for the Yufeng and Yuehua.
これでバカじゃなければ 本当に
玉鳳 楽華(がくか)の強敵になるだろうに
Well, I guess this is sorta the color of the Feixin Unit.
まあ でも―
これが飛信隊の色といえば色か
あっ… １人落ちてきたぞ！
One person fell!
Ow...
あいてて…
（魏兵）ぶっ殺せ！
（信）うん？
Kill him!
Oh, oh no!
い… いかん！
信どのが袋のネズミに！
Lord Xin is like a rat in a trap!
Let's go, everyone!
行くぞ みんな！
Er, go? How?
（尾平）
えっ？ 行くって どうやって？
Please just run away for now, Lord Xin!
ひ… ひとまず
逃げてください 信どの！
Ah, that's the State of Qin flag!
（崇原）あっ！ あれは秦国の旗！
They made it through the South castle wall!
（去亥）南の城壁を抜いたんだ！
When did they...?
いつの間に…
Against that showy siege tower, the enemy split up their soldiers.
派手な井蘭車に対し
敵は 兵を割いていた
So it's natural they'd be short on hands.
ほかが手薄になっていたのは当然だ
しかも―
And what's more...
That is Thousand-Man General Guo Bei.
あれは郭備(かくび)千人将の部隊
Meaning someone of the core class of the Main Army has arrived.
つまり 本軍主力級の実力者の
登場というわけだ
ハッ…
ボ～ッとしてる場合じゃねえ
This isn't the time to be spacing out!
Hey, you bastards!
おい てめえら さっさと下りてこい
また手柄取られちまうぞ！
Hurry the hell down here!
We're gonna get our achievements taken from us again!
（兵士たち）お… おう！
R-Right!
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）
その後 城内へ突入した飛信隊は
After that, the Feixin Unit coincidentally ran into an enemy's famed military commander and crushed him.
偶然 名のある武将と遭遇し
これを撃破
As a result, they rendered achievements greater than the Yufeng Unit or the Yuehua Unit.
結果的に 玉鳳隊 楽華隊よりも
大きな武功を上げたのである
You bastards! We may not have gotten the general's head,
野郎ども！ 大将首は逃(のが)したが
but let's set that aside for now and celebrate!
それは ひとまず置いといて 祝杯だ
（兵士たち）オーッ！
It was somewhat due to luck,
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）
運によるところもあったが
but the Feixin Unit was honestly happy for their first military achievement in quite some time.
飛信隊は
この久々の武功を素直に喜んだ
But the way you fell was really something, Captain!
（崇原）しかし
隊長の落ちっぷりは見事だったな
るせえ！ …つうか 竜川！
てめえ ちょっと来い！
Shut up!
And anyhow, Long Chuan, come here for a second!
ハハハハッ！ あれで
ケガしねえってのは さすが信だ
Only you could end up unscathed after that, Xin!
（田有）それより 井蘭車
最後 車輪ぶっ壊れてたぞ
But anyhow, that siege tower!
The wheels broke down in the end.
It broke?! For real?
壊れた？ マジかよ？
Yeah. That old man from Yufeng was teary-eyed.
（松左(しょうさ)）ああ
玉鳳のじいさん 涙目だったぞ
（尾平）
ア～ハハッ！ ざまあみやがれ！
Serves them right!
Oh, so they're the Feixin Unit?
（郭備）オッ… 彼らが飛信隊か
Huh? Who's that?
（去亥）うん？ 誰だ？ ありゃ
Lord Guo Bei, please hurry!
（部下）
郭備さま お急ぎを　軍議が…
The war council!
（竜有(りゅうゆう)）郭備？
Guo Bei?
（郭備）
すぐに行く　先に行っててくれ
I'll be right there.
Go on ahead.
（田永(でんえい)）郭備っていえば 今日
大将首を挙げたっていう千人将じゃ
Isn't Guo Bei the Thousand-Man General that took the enemy general's head today?
X-Xin...
（尾平）し… 信
（兵士）隊長
Captain!
So you're Xin?
君が信か
フッ… 思ってたとおりの風貌だ
You look just as I expected.
I've heard you used to be a servant.
君は 下僕の出らしいな
（信）ンッ…
Ever since I heard that, I've had something I wanted to tell you.
（郭備）それを耳にしてから
ずっと伝えたいことがあった
ンッ… んだよ？ 言ってみろ
What? Say it then!
フッ…
この郭備も 下僕の出身だ
I, Guo Bei, was originally a servant as well.
Like you, I lost my parents to a war.
（郭備）
君と同じく 戦で親を亡くしてな
Since I was a small child, I worked as a servant for various different families,
幼少より
いろんな家の下僕を転々として―
and was eventually taken in by my current family that originally didn't have any children.
子供のいなかった今の家が
養子にしてくれた
Now I'm a comrade to those in the warrior class.
それで 今は士族の仲間入りだ
When I heard about your circumstances, it reminded me of my younger self.
君の境遇を聞き
昔の自分を思い出してな
それ以来 ずっと君を応援していた
I've been cheering you on ever since then.
But to become a 300-Man General without any support, and so young, is quite impressive.
しかし 何の後ろ盾もなく―
しかも その若さで
よく三百人将になったな
You're really giving it your all.
本当に頑張っている
（信）えっ… いや 俺は…
N-No, I...
I was impressed by how you cut down that man Luan Tong at Guolong Castle.
高狼(こうろう)城で
あの乱銅(らんどう)を斬ったことにも感心した
Did you realize?
気づいたか？
（信）えっ？
Thanks to that, there weren't as many violations, it seems.
あのおかげで
この城では あんな蹂躙(じゅうりん)行為は―
ほとんど なかったみたいだぞ
（どよめき）
All right, Xin!
やったな 信！
（信）ああ
Yeah!
Ah, h-hang on!
（信）あっ… ちょ… ちょっと
I took it upon myself to try to help you out,
（郭備）何か力になってやろうと
勝手に思っていたが
フフッ… 要らぬ世話だったようだ
（信）えっ？
but it seems I don't need to.
This unit is no fluke. Keep moving forward.
この隊は間違ってない
このまま進め
Let's not lose to any nobles or warrior class families, Xin!
貴士族なんかに負けるなよ 信
Meng Tian had mentioned,
（尾平）蒙恬が言ってたぜ
知 武 勇
全て そろった郭備千人将は―
Thousand-Man General Guo Bei is a popular general with intelligence, strength and bravery all in one.
人望も篤(あつ)く
秦国軍の中でも極めて逸材
An outstanding talent even among the State of Qin Army.
若い将校の中じゃ
今いちばん将軍に近い武将だって
And that among the young officers, he's the military commander closest to general right now.
Apparently he's already a close associate to Great General Meng Ao in this war.
この戦いじゃ 既に 蒙驁大将軍の
側近のひとりになってるらしいぜ
He's a Thousand-Man General, but he's already an aide to a Great General...
（竜有）千人将の身で
もう大将軍の側近って…
しかも まだ相当 若かったぞ
And he's still pretty young, too.
（去亥）
下僕出身には 全然 見えなかったな
For someone that started as a servant, that's something I've never seen before.
He's excelling past the warrior class people around him.
そこらの貴族よりサマになってます
But he still seemed like such a pleasant person.
（昂(こう)）
だけど 全然 嫌みのない人だった
いるんだな ああいう人も
I guess there are guys like that, too.
Thousand-Man General Guo Bei...
郭備千人将…
Thousand-Man General Guo Bei, please wait.
（男性）郭備千人将 お待ちを
（郭備）うん？
Hm, who was next?
（輪虎）え～っと…
次は誰だっけ？
Preview
Air of a Military
Commander
End